Finding Aid of the Alice Lavinia Long Papers LSC.2092
UCLA Library Special Collections
Alice Lavinia Long papers
ca. 1924-1967
UCLA Library Special Collections
Long, Alice Lavinia
LSC.2092
1 Linear Feet (2 boxes)
Alice Lavinia Knoblauch married Haniel Clark Long in 1913. She painted, wove, and wrote poetry, which her husband collected and preserved. A collection of her poetry was privately printed (1967). The collection consists of manuscript material, printed material relating to Alice Long, correspondence, and ephemera. Manuscripts include The poems of Alice Lavinia Long, Alice's journal, and Christmas, 1939.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Anton V. Long, 1973 & 1976.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9922210333606533
Biography
Alice Lavinia Knoblauch was born in Minneapolis, Minnesota; married Haniel Clark Long there on Aug. 12, 1913; after Long resigned his position at Carnegie Institute of Technology, they moved in 1929 to Santa Fe, New Mexico; she painted, wove, and wrote poetry, which her husband collected and preserved; she died on October 14, 1956 in Santa Fe; The poems of Alice Lavinia Long was privately printed in 1967.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of manuscript material, printed material relating to Alice Long, correspondence, and ephemera. Manuscripts include The poems of Alice Lavinia Long, Alice's journal, and Christmas, 1939. Correspondents include Clifton Fadiman, Lawrence Clark Powell, and May Sarton.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
The poems of Alice Lavinia Long (Box 1).
Printed material re Long, typescripts of journal, poems, and ephemera (Box 1).
Letters from various persons to Anton Long re The poems of Alice Lavinia Long, ca. 1967 (Box 2).
Women poets, American -- Archives.; Manuscripts for publication; Long, Alice Lavinia, -1956--Archives.
- The poems of Alice Lavinia Long. Naples, New York, 1967 (Box 1)
  - Typescript and copies with printer's instructions., 11 p.l., 55 leaves. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General note
    Title page entitled "Final draft and dummy."
  - Galley proofs., 1 p.l., 55 leaves. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Typescript and copies., 43 miscellaneous leaves. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Miscellaneous clippings re Alice Long., (2 items) (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Letters re The poems of Alice Lavinia Long. n.p., 1967-1978.; 3 items. Typescript carbon. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes letter Vitter Bynner and 1 clipping.
  [Also], holograph fragment of poem by Alice Lavinia Long.
- Ephemera re The poems of Alice Lavinia Long., (11 items) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Includes typescript carbon of letter to recipients of the book.
- Invoices re The poems of Alice Lavinia Long., (4 items) (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Encore. A quarterly of verse and poetic arts vol.2, no.3. Albuquerque, New Mexico., (Spring 1968, February-April) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  "Alice Long Memorial" (pp.4-6).
- "She left so gently (for Alice Long)." National Fraternal Club News Magazine, (June 6, 1974).; p.4 (1 leaf) Photocopy. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Private joy. Sayings of the children Molly and John. Recorded by their mother, 1926. Saint Paul, Minnesota: The Webb Press, 1942.; 9 p.l., 58pp. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Related publications, v.p., v.d.; (6 items) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1) Anthology of poetry and verse by Institute of American Indian Arts students. Santa Fe, New Mexico: U.S. Department of the Interior, 1965. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 2) A brief history and guide, Old South Church in Boston. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 3) "Mystical union of writer and region" [review of Southwest Classics by Lawrence Clark Powell]. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 4) In memoriam: Haniel Long. Supplement to the Sunstone Review, Christmas 1974. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 5) "Invoi to Fred Demmler." Reprint from Southwest Review vol.60, no.4., (Autumn 1975); 2 copies. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Manuscript Material (Box 1, Folder 14-16)
  - Alice's journal, 1949-1951.; 112 leaves. Typescript. In brown cover. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Extracted from letters to various persons.
  - Alice's poems. From about, 1924-[1954].; 78 leaves. Typescript. Loose leaf notebook. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Christmas, 1939. [Santa Fe], 1 leaf. Typescript carbon. (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Haniel Long Fund. Checkbook and accounts paid. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  re publication of The poems of Alice Lavinia Long.
- [Correspondence]. v.p., [], 1923-1956; (37 items) (Box 1)
  - Letters to Mrs. Hattie L. Knoblauch. v.p., 1923-1941.; (9 items) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Letters from various persons. v.p., 1934-1956.; (28 items) (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Letters from various persons to Anton Long as The poems of Alice Lavinia Long., ca. 1967. (Box 2)
- A - C., (40 items) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Includes letters from Anton Long to:
  Witter Bynner
  Garth Cate
  Peggy Pond Church
- D - G., (35 items) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Includes letters from:
  Clifton Fadiman
  Mrs. Turlie May (John Gould Fletcher)
- H - L., (27 items) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Includes letter from:
  Margaret Burke Kiskadden
- M - Q., (29 items) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Lawrence Clark Powell
- R - Z., (25 items) (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Includes Letter from:
  May Sarton
- T - Z., (24 items) (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Jean Starr Untermeyer
- Letters of acknowledgement from various institutions regarding receipt of The poems of Alice Lavinia Long. v.p., ca. 1967.; (10 items) (Box 2, Folder 7)